What you want, when you want it.
KMBC on demand, from the voice
of Kansas City. News radio.
[radio playing]
- Sandra Day O' Connor,
the first woman ever
to serve on the High Court
has turned in letter of resignation,
bringing her career
on the High Court to an end.
Let's go to the White House.
- Good morning.
I've directed my staff
to compile information
and recommend for my review,
potential nominees who will
faithfully interpret the constitution
and laws of our country.
[radio playing]
- I believe as Christian citizens
of this country,
that we should be
actively involved in this,
this historic moment.
And if the church across this country,
believers can come together
and take a stand,
I think it's gonna have a powerful,
powerful impact on this process.
[radio playing]
- We dare not sleep
through this point of decision,
because frankly,
future generations depend on us.
Pray urgently that God's perfect will,
will be done.
- We are engaged today
in what they call, "Culture War."
We didn't start it but, we, by his grace,
are going to end it and we should say,
"Yes! We want to reclaim
America for Christ!"
♪ [music] ♪
- Up in the pulpit,
this means spirited message,
"Us and against them,"
and that's what the religious rightist
are doing in the United States now.
It is dividing this country.
Alright, we have Tyre.
- Yes.
- in Hillside, Illinois,
who listens on WCPT
What do you have on your mind?
I'm a Christian.
I'm a Bible believing Christian.
Somehow, these guys
don't jive with the Christianity
and what I've learned.
I mean, there is an authoritarian
kind of way about them
and there's nothing gentle,
there's nothing compassionate.
To me, there's nothing
Christian about them.
- Yeah.
- I mean...
- It's upside down. I mean, yeah,
I've been raised a Christian all my life.
I think that's probably the thing that
upsets me most about what's happening.
- None, yeah, none of it
really makes any sense to me.
- Yeah. There's some new brand
of religion out there.
That somehow, things have changed
since Matthew wrote about
Jesus' Sermon on the Mount,
where Jesus told us to be peacemakers.
Right now, everything they do,
they say they do in the name of God.
That we need to go to war
in the name of God.
They're being told that
George Bush, of all people,
is a holy man whose been anointed
with the job
of creating a Christian society,
not just in America
but all over the world.
- You and I know that's bull.
There's this entanglement
of politics with religion.
What kind of lesson
is that for our children?
Jesus Camp
♪ [music] ♪
There's never been
a generation like this one.
The Earth is filled with the dead dying,
in spirit and in body.
But now is the time
for the glory of the Lord
to cover the Earth
as the water covers the seas.
[together] Now is the time!
We prophesize these dry bones. Arise!
Speak the word of the Lord.
♪ [music] ♪
[audience clapping]
- Fabulous! All right.
Thank you for coming!
That is great. Wow!
I have no idea how many people
are here today.
I'm told the auditorium will hold
about 500 hundred,
so were doing pretty good,
aren't we?
Okay, listen. Moms and Dads.
I wanna tell you about some of the things
we have in the bookstore.
We have the School Of Evangelism
and unfortunately,
this one doesn't sell quite as much
because people,
for whatever reason that,
I guess they think
this is gonna be a "Door Knocking" manual,
and it's not.
There's a hands on manual
in the back that teaches kids
how to actually start a conversation
with their friends
and how to win the lost.
Another thing that I wanted to announce
is our camp, coming up in August.
[people cheering]
Yeah! And it's just gonna be
an incredible time.
We've got brochures on the camps,
sitting in the bookstore.
You need to pick one up
and begin praying about
whether or not you can
get there this year. Okay?
Boys and girls!
I know everybody is sitting up straight,
handsome and smiling faces,
looking right this way.
Is there anyone in here that believes
that God can do anything?
God can do anything!
We can just say, "God! Fix the world!"
How many of you know
that this is a pretty sick old world?
This is a sick old world.
Well, then let's just fix it!
Somebody get your tools out
and let's just fix this old world!
Kids, you gotta change things!
We got too many Christian grown ups that
are fat and lazy!
[children laughing]
They don't want to give up
their evening meal.
They don't want to fast
for a three day fast
or a 40 day fast or whatever.
Do you know that Muslims
train their children
from the time they're 5 years old,
to fast during the month of Ramadan.
Listen. We hold the keys.
We can change the world.
Boys and girls can change the world!
Absolutely!
[audience clapping]
[children cheering]
Let's stand to our feet.
Hallelujah!
I need you to get serious,
serious with God. Say, "God."
[together] God!
I'm here to be trained.
[together] I'm here to be trained.
I'm here for an education!
[together] I'm here for an education.
I'm willing God.
[together] I'm willing God.
I'll do what you want me to do!
[together] I'll do what you want me to do.
I'll say what you want me to say!
[together] I'll say
what you want me to say.
In Jesus name.
[together] In Jesus name.
Amen.
[together] Amen.
If you don't open your mouth,
the Holy Spirit can't talk.
All right, now I want everyone
to raise your hands
and we're gonna pray in tongues.
Hallelujah! Let's do it.
Oh, we love you Jesus.
[foreign language]
[children talking]
Lord! Let the Holy Spirit fall.
He's here!
Feel his power. Feel his power!
You talk to him
and the Holy Spirit is just gonna whisper
in your ear what to say.
[foreign language]
- You have to ask her!
- Don't stop! Don't stop!
This is the greatest day of your life,
next to the day you got saved.
[foreign language]
She's not in a trance.
She's not out of it.
She's very aware of what's going on.
She's just hooking up with the Spirit.
She's just staying focused.
Becky Fischer is a Pentecostal
children's minister.
She runs conferences
and an annual summer camp
for Evangelical kids.
[voices from the TV]
I can go into a playground of kids
that don't know
anything about Christianity.
Lead them to the Lord in a matter of
just no time at all
and just moments later,
they can be seeing visions
and hearing the voice of God
because they're so open.
They are so usable in Christianity.
[people talking]
If you look at the world's population,
1/3 of that 6.7 billion people
are children under the age of 15.
One-third.
Where should we be putting our efforts?
Where should we be putting our focus?
I'll tell you where our enemies
are putting it.
They're putting it on the kids.
They're going into the schools.
You go into Palestine
and I can take you to some websites
that will absolutely shake you
to your foundations
and show you photographs of where
they're taking their kids to camps,
like we take our kids to bible camps
and they're putting
hand grenades in their hands.
They're teaching them
how to put on bomb belts.
They're teaching them how to use rifles.
They're teaching them how to
use machine guns.
It's no wonder, with that kind
of intense training and discipling,
that those young people are ready
to kill themselves for the cause
of Islam.
[kids screaming]
I wanna see young people who are
as committed to the cause of Jesus Christ
as the young people are
to the cause of Islam
I wanna see them as radically laying down
their lives for the gospel
as they are over in Pakistan, in Israel,
in Palestine and all those
different places.
You know, because we have, excuse me,
but we have the truth!
[music playing]
I would say there's
a friendlier environment now
in the United States towards Christianity
than there has been in my lifetime.
And a lot of it has to do,
just in the last few years,
has to do with President Bush.
He has really brought some
real credibility to the Christian faith.
He's been very open,
blatantly open, in his faith in God.
This moment, right now - today,
is a fulfillment of prophecy.
We've got to stand up
and take back the land.
[music playing]
Hey listen! I just wanted
to know you guys more.
Now both of you came with Mark, right?
-Yep!
- And he's your children's pastor?
- Yes.
- But you're not related to him, right?
-No.
- He's coming to our camp this summer.
Are you guys coming too?
- [together] To North Dakota?
- To North Dakota.
- [together] Yes.
- You are coming?
- Totally cool!
Is your whole family coming
or just you guys?
- I think just us.
- Awesome!
- Like my brother, my twin brother.
- Okay. I wanna know more
about you guys.
How long have you been a Christian?
- I've been a Christian at...
I was-- at 5, I got saved.
- Yeah?
- Because I just wanted more of life.
- Yeah.
- Because there was nothing
that I thought was fun.
- You thought at 5 years old
there was nothing fun?
- Yes.
- Really? Already.
- Yeah, at 5 years old.
- So what do you think
this camp is gonna be like?
What are you expecting?
What are you expecting
God to do for you?
- What am I expecting God will do for me?
- Yeah, at camp.
- I think, oh, at camp. At camp,
I think God is gonna get me used
to meeting other people because
I have a hard time with that.
- I can't believe that!
- I'm shy.
- You're shy. Can't believe it.
- Except for when things are happening
in the Holy Spirit.
- Yeah! Then you're not shy at all.
- No.
- Oh, you guys are great.
Really appreciate you coming.
- All right.
- Can't wait to see you again this summer.
Give me a hug. All right.
- Good to meet you, Teren.
Good to meet you, Levi.
I'll talk to you later
- Okay!
- Buh-bye.
♪ [music] ♪
Evangelicals believe that
to obtain salvation,
they must be "Born-again"
by accepting Jesus as their savior.
Forty three percent
of Evangelical Christians
become "born-again"
before the age of 13.
[cars passing by]
Time of creation, Garden of Eden.
Approximately, 6000 years ago.
[explosion]
Was it an explosion?
Did we come from a glob of goo?
Ewww! I don't think so.
It's been said that we are
the result of an explosion.
Is this true? Is this scientific
or is it just based on a belief?
- Levi! Come here.
I need to be near you.
- All right. Let's go over some things.
One popular thing to do
in American politics
is to note that the summers
in the United States
over the past few years
have been very warm.
As a result, global warming must be real.
What's wrong with this reasoning?
- It's only got up 0.6 degrees.
- Yeah, it's not really
a big problem, is it?
- No. I don't think
that it's gonna hurt us.
It's a huge political issue.
Global warming is
and that's why it's really important
for you to understand--
- Is evolution, too?
- Um, not really as much--
- Creationism?
- Um, it's becoming one now.
What if you had to go to a school
where the teacher said,
"Creationism is something stupid!
And you're stupid if you believe in it!"
- I think they should let them.
- Well, or what if you had to go
to a school where your teacher said,
"Evolution is stupid!
And you're stupid if you believe in it!"
- I wouldn't mind it.
- You wouldn't mind that.
If you look at creationism, you realize
it's the only possible answer
to all the questions.
- That's exactly what Dad said!
- It's the only possible answer
to all the questions.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, yeah!
- Yes.
[laughs]
- Did you get to the part on here
where it says that
science doesn't prove anything?
And it's really interesting
when you look at it that way.
- It is.
- It is!
- All right!
- I think personally
that Galileo made the right choice
by giving up Science for Christ.
[music playing]
[water running]
- God didn't say,
"Have children and give my kids
to someone else for 8 hours a day."
If I can home school them as well
as the school can public school them,
why would I send them
somewhere else for 8 hours a day?
Our nation was founded
on Judeo-Christian values.
We know when things started changing.
You know, prayer got taken out of school
and the school started falling apart.
Now the rest of us are going,
"Wait a minute.
Where is my country?"
Our firm belief is there are two kinds
of people in the world.
People who love Jesus
and people who don't.
And I want my kids to grow up knowing,
"You know what?
It's a good thing to be Christian."
[radio playing]
- Tomorrow, Glen Thomas, gives us
a first hand perspective
from Christian marines involved
in Operation Iraqi Freedom
in his book "God Saw Them Through."
So tomorrow oughta be very interesting.
We'll see you back here then.
[radio playing]
-Why are kids taught that global warming
doesn't exist?
Okay, why? Look, rape this world.
Rape this Earth.
Take everything you want from it
because, you know what,
it doesn't matter!
We're not here for very long.
Christ is coming to take us away
from Earth.
So cut down our trees.
Use all of our oil.
Take advantage of everything that
the Earth has to offer.
That's why you hear them getting involved
with issues like global warming.
You wanna shake them and you wanna say,
"What,what is it
that you're not understanding
about the fundamentals of Christianity?"
"How did you get here?"
Our President is still
telling Americans that
we should teach creationism
in our schools.
That we should teach it right along side
with evolution.
- I think we've become
absolutely complacent in this
and I think that they're composing
exactly what they want!
- Do you know what's happening in Kansas?
- Oh, I know. I saw that.
- They have to teach intelligent design
right along with Darwin's evolution.
Well, think about that?
You got 600,000 children
that are being lied to.
- There is no conflict between the two.
- Well, I...
- That religion is not science.
- We have a population, 25% out of the
American population right now
describe themselves as Evangelicals.
That's about, about 80 million people.
They're very tenacious,
and they elbow their way
into positions of power in America.
That is the M. O. of a group
that is committed to -
like I say - building a government
that they're comfortable with.
In the end, it's gonna come like thief
in the night.
There's this slow chipping away
at the separation
between church and state.
[cars passing by]
[music playing]
[people talking]
[cheering]
Jesus died and was buried.
Three days later, he rose from the dead.
Wasn't Jesus only a man? No.
Jesus Christ is Almighty God.
- Come on, Rachel.
- Rachel, it's your turn.
- I know!
- Go ahead, Rachel.
- There you go, Rachel. Get a strike.
- Yeah, yeah! Get it strike this time!
[music playing]
- Jesus. Jesus.
Your Spirit would help to make this
one a good one.
Ball, I command you to - in the name
of Jesus. Make a good hit!
- Alright! Rachel!
[hands clapping]
[people talking]
- This side of it to bowl.
- Okay.
- Hi. God is telling me
that you're on His mind
and He just wants to take you
and He just wants to love on you
and He has special plans for you,
in your life.
He just wants you to be able to follow
Him with your whole heart.
- Thank you!
- Your welcome.
- Appreciate it.
- Welcome.
- Wow! So you saw her need
and felt like God told you
to go over there.
- Yeah! I waited a little bit.
You know, to be sure.
You know what I mean.
- Kept coming into your heart.
- Uh huh. And afterwards I felt like
I had picked the right one.
- All right! Good job, Rachel.
Trying to be obedient.
[laughs]
- I like bowling ministry. There we go!
When I grow up, I just -
I always thought it would be kind of fun
to be one of those like, people
who paint nails and stuff
because you would get a chance
to tell them about the Lord.
I mean, just relaxing
Christian music in the background.
You know, doing it.
You know what I mean?
It would just be really relaxing
and they would just be able to--
they won't have
many walls at that second.
They would just be able
to accept, you know?
I've been teased several times
and I just thought to myself,
"Man's decision? Whatever!
God's decision. Something!"
They think I'm weird, go ahead.
"You're not the ones
who are gonna be judging me
if I'm going to hell or heaven.
God is. It matters what he thinks of me.
Doesn't matter what you think."
[exhales hard]
[vehicles passing]
[music playing]
This is my favorite part.
My favorite kind of music
is like Christian heavy metal,
rock and roll.
It focuses in the basis
towards Jesus
and some of the songs don't actually
say like "Jesus" or "Our Lord"
or stuff like that.
But they do have a Christian basis
and it is focused towards him
so that's why I like Christian and, but--
really Britney Spears
and like Lindsay Lohan and stuff
people like that.
I could definitely care less about them
because their main --
their songs are mainly based
on either like guys or girls and...
We as Christians -
I do not believe in that.
[music playing]
- Victoria.
- Yeah?
- Can you wrap it up in about five minutes
so I can feed you, lunch.
- Yeah.
- When I dance, I really have to make sure
that that's God because people will notice
when I'm just dancing for the flesh
and I do that sometimes.
I must admit that and I really need
to get over that.
I'm not the, I'm not the only one
who makes makes that--
People out there, they're not the only one
who makes that mistake.
- Can you have a cookie?
You can have a cookie.
- Can I have a cookie?
Okay. All right.
Let's the Pledge of Allegiance first
now that everybody is--
before we get on to something else.
Jenny. Christian.
Will you stand up please? Okay.
[together] I pledge allegiance
to the Christian flag,
to the Savior, to his Kingdom it stands.
One brotherhood, uniting all Christians
in idea and in love.
- Okay. Put your hand on the bible.
[together] I pledge allegiance
to the Bible, God's holy word.
I will make it a lamp unto my feet
and a light unto my path.
I will hide it's word in my heart
that I might not sin against God.
- Here.
- Very good everybody.
I look at it, and George does too,
our children are on loan
to us from God and someday,
we're gonna have to answer to God
about how we raised our children.
I'm like,
"Lord, you've given me this daughter
and how am I supposed to train her?
What am I supposed to do now?"
Right? I bring her to places where
she can learn this, from Becky,
from Pastor Care, from different people.
But the Lord told me what you need
to train her and is to train
her about character.
- Where are you going?
- I just have stand out in the rain.
- Okay. Okay, you stood on the rain.
- I didn't get wet yet.
- Well, I don't want you
to get soaking wet.
Victoria, turn around
and go back inside now. Thanks!
- Eight, nine, ten.
Okay, I got to get hit 10 times
by drops of rain because I'm 10 years old.
- You're very funny.
[rain gushing]
[hangers shuffling]
- Tory, okay, let's go
get your stuff packed. Come on!
So Annie, here we go!
Getting all ready for camp. Okay.
Tory, we need to get out
your sleeping bag.
You need a Bible,
a pen and a notebook.
Flashlight.
Oh! You're "Breathe Prophecy" dance stuff.
- Right!
- All right, did you find the leotard yet?
Check in your... Yeah, check in there.
[lock clicking]
[car passing]
[music playing]
In 2001, Pastor Becky Fischer started
the "Kids on Fire" summer camp
in Devil's Lake, North Dakota.
Evangelical families from
around the country attend.
Let's just walk around the pews
and stuff and just pray over the seats.
Yeah. Yeah.
In the name of Jesus,
we just speak over every person
that's sitting on these chairs this week.
Lord, we just ask them to be
covered with the blood of Jesus.
Open hearts, Lord. Open hearts.
Father, we pray
over the electrical systems.
We pray over the electricity will not
go out in this building in Jesus' name,
because of storms
or any other reason.
I just pray over this equipment.
We speak over
the PowerPoint presentations,
all of the video projectors,
and we say "Devil, we know
what you love to do in meetings like this
and we say, you will not,
in Jesus name,
you will not prevent this message
from going out."
No microphone problems, in Jesus name.
In the name of Jesus, we speak that.
[speaking in foreign language]
Father, we just ask you
in the mighty name of Jesus
that this would be
defining moment in their lives.
Father, I pray that Jesus
will be glorified on this camp.
[music playing]
[car passing by]
♪ [music] ♪
[people talking]
[sigh]
I get exhausted doing this.
♪ [music] ♪
[clapping hands]
♪ You tell me ♪
♪ Who's in the house? ♪
♪ JC ♪
♪ Tell me ♪
♪ Who's in the house? ♪
- C'mon.
♪ JC ♪
♪ Who's in the house? ♪
♪ Jesus Christ is in the house today ♪
♪ [music] ♪
♪ Dance ♪
♪ We're kicking it for Christ ♪
♪ I say it's Jesus Christ ♪
♪ He's in the house ♪
♪ Today ♪
- Whoa! Give yourself a big, big hand.
[clapping hand]
- Good evening!
[together] Good evening.
- You made it!
[people cheering]
How do you guys like the hair?
[people clapping]
Finger nails?
[people cheering]
The eyebrows?
And the rest of me.
[people laughing]
See we're talking this week
about how the Devil uses tactics
to destroy our lives.
The first tactic that he uses
is to tempt you with sin.
You see when you first start out
as a kid, particularly,
because that's when all this stuff starts.
When you start out as a kid,
sin just doesn't seem that big of a deal.
It looks kind of cute, in fact.
Warm and fuzzy.
But sin is designed to destroy you
and you feed this baby long enough,
and he's gonna grow in your life
until you got yourself
a tiger by the tail, and you don't know
which end is up.
What used to seem very innocent
now controls your life.
The Devil goes after the young,
those who cannot fend for themselves.
That's why we're trying to help you.
We're trying to warn you.
And while I'm on this subject,
let me say something about Harry Potter,
warlocks are enemies of God.
[people talking]
- And I don't care
what kind of hero they are,
they're an enemy of God
and had it been in the old testament,
Harry Potter would have been
put to death!
- Amen!
[people clapping]
You don't make heroes out of warlocks!
This is a generation
that's gonna stand for purity,
and righteousness, and holiness,
and you're gonna serve the Lord
all the days of your life.
And we declare all those things over you.
I believe this so much that
I have given my whole life
to see to it that you get there.
I sense in my heart tonight,
what I heard the Lord say
is that there's some kids here
that say they're Christians
that go to church all the time
but you're one thing when you're
at church and you're another thing
when you're at school with your friends.
You're phoney and a hypocrite.
You do things you shouldn't do.
You talk dirty
just like all the other kids talk dirty,
and it's time to clean up your act.
Come up here and get washed
because we can't have phonies
in the Army of God.
If that's you, put your hands up here.
Whoa, baby. Wash your hands.
Father, we just wash them
with the water of your word.
We say, "No more, Devil! No more!"
Say it boys and girls,
in the name of Jesus.
You know exactly
what you need to repent on.
Name it! Name it out loud. Name it!
What do you need to be forgiven of?
♪ [woman singing] ♪
No more wishy washy!
No more hypocrisy!
Now you go somewhere and pray
and you start doing some repenting here.
[clapping hands]
[people murmuring]
- I haven't got much to say.
I just wanted to talk about belief in God
and I've had a hard time doing it.
And...It's just really hard to do this.
Just to believe in God is really hard
because you don't see him.
You don't really know him much.
Sometimes, I don't even believe
what the Bible says.
It makes me a faker,
it makes me feel guilty and bad
'cause God has always talked to me
about that.
I can't inject it in.
♪ [music] ♪
[thunder]
[rain splashing]
[children playing]
Boo!
[children laughing]
[child whispering]
- In a dark, dark house,
there was a dark, dark hallway.
In the dark, dark hallway,
there was a dark, dark room.
In the dark, dark room,
there was a dark, dark staircase.
- Coach.
- Everybody in their bed?
- I'm not.
- All right.
- I'm not gonna do it!
I've got a__.
- I'm not that wild
about ghost stories, okay?
Some of them are a lot of fun
but they don't, maybe honor God.
And God says to focus
on those things that are-- that bear truth
and those things that have beauty.
Focus on the good things
and things of God, okay?
Here we go, lights out guys.
[door closes]
[birds chirping]
- What time is breakfast?
- 0800
- My hair is still wet.
[taps on keyboard]
God just created humans. They ate from
the Tree of the Knowledge
of good and evil,
resulted in sin and death.
I got some dripping with blood
here somewhere.
There, that looks better
and I want to move these there.
That's better.
This generation particularly is a sight
and sound generation.
And so it's very difficult for them
to sit down with a book,
a tablet and pencil
and try to learn the way we've learned.
They learn visually,
they learn by demonstration,
they learn by modelling.
So, here's our Adam and Eve,
ain't that great?
Just a good old Ken and Barbie doll,
and so we talk about how they walked
and talked in the Garden of Eden with God
but when God breathed into Man,
into his nostrils, the breath of life...
[whoosh]
At that point, Man became a living soul.
Now, I tell the kids,
if you want to become a stronger Christian
and have your Spirit Man be strong,
there's certain things you need to do.
If you pray everyday,
[whoosh]
your Spirit Man will get stronger.
If you go to church
and learn more about God.
[whoosh]
You're spirit is gonna get stronger.
If you don't read the Bible,
come on, its gotta speak.
Ah, wrong balloon!
[squeaking]
You're spirit will get weaker.
So...For instance,
we have a brain mold
because one of the sessions
is gonna be talking about our minds
and how they need to be renewed
towards the word of God.
This is really fun
because you can make a Jello-O mold
that looks like a brain
and then you just talk about
how things stick to our minds.
We use this sticky fingers and so
this would represent dirty thoughts.
This would represent swear words.
This would represent things
that we've seen on T. V.
or whatever that we've heard
and it sticks to our minds
and then you're supposed to slap it--
Woops.
- On the brain?
- I don't know if it slaps--
if it's gonna stick very good
but, well, there, it's sticking to the--
there, it sticks to your brain
and that's very effective for kids.
So, I mean there's different things
that we've gotten but that's what I do.
I just go look around,
I walk around the toy section of stores
or I'll see something and I'll go,
"That really would work good for..."
You know, so, I come at it
with 20 object lessons
and I preach for an hour, you know.
And people--
other children's ministers are going,
"Preaching to an hour for kids,"
and they feel sorry for the kids.
You don't need to feel sorry for my kids.
They know exactly, you know,
they're getting it.
They're getting it.
[children shouting]
- I got teeth, yes I do.
I got teeth and how about you?
I got teeth and how about you all?
[together] I got teeth, yes I do.
I got teeth and how about you?
- One two!
- One, two, three, four.
We got teeth and we want more.
- Everybody ready?
We're gonna pray again.
All right, God we just thank you
for this food this morning.
We just ask you, Father, to bless it
and Lord Jesus, we bleed your blood
over our sins
and the sins of our nation.
God, end abortion
and send revival to America.
Thank you, Jesus! Amen!
- Mom, doesn't he look like Harry Potter?
- Mom, he looks like Harry Potter.
- A bit, yes.
[child laughing]
- I can't watch it
because it has witchcraft.
- Well, my mom doesn't
want me to watch any of the movies
'cause there's witchcraft
but I watch with my Dad.
- This is Becky Fisher.
- This is Becky Fisher, live
and in color, all right?
- Look at the new hairstyle.
She's the number one cover lady
for Children's Ministry worldwide.
Brave girl.
[laughing]
- It's almost like being
on the cover of Rolling Stones.
♪ [music] ♪
[girl humming]
So far, camp has been awesome!
I love being in the presence of God.
[scratching noise]
God is not in every church.
There is such a thing, they're called--
as a certain churches,
they're called Dead Churches.
And the people there,
they sit there like this,
"We worship you, God.
We worship you, God."
They sing like 3 songs
and they listen to a sermon.
Churches that God likes to go to
are churches where
they're jumping up and down,
shouting his name,
and just praising him.
They're not acting.
They're not quiet.
"We worship you."
They're, "Hallelujah God!"
You know?
And depending on what-- how they
invite him, he'll be there or not.
[tapping sound]
V-I-C-T-O-R-Y.
That's the Trojan battle cry.
[together] V-I-C-T-O-R-Y.
[tapping sound]
Got my Bible.
They told me I was gonna preach tonight.
I'm really excited preaching to kids.
I've never really preached
a whole bunch of kids that I didn't know.
[pages turning]
I feel, I mean, I really feel...
I really feel that we're a key generation,
I really do.
I really feel that
that this generation is a key generation
to Jesus coming back.
That is exactly what I want to say.
[tapping sound]
I don't write the sermon.
God writes the sermon.
I mean, I can feel
that sometimes when I'm writing,
I could feel it in my arm.
Someone's holding my arm
when I'm writing, right?
Now, when I go up there
and I start preaching,
the Holy Spirit is going
to come out of me.
That ain't gonna be me
up there preaching.
It is, but you know,
it's not gonna be me.
[laughs]
And you know,
we can't just sit around
on the couch all day
because Satan will be after you.
He's not gonna sit around either.
Satan is not staying around,
you shouldn't be sitting around.
Satan will trip you off your path,
off of your race, off the course.
Don't let him do that.
In Jesus name,
do not let Satan get you off
what God has for you.
We are a generation
that needs to rise up.
That needs to rise up
and run without the time.
Run with our whole heart.
Everything we've got.
- Yeah!
[audience clapping]
- Now...
Who's ready
for some fun tonight?
[kids cheering]
You're not gonna be the same person
that you came on this camp.
You're gonna be a different person.
You're gonna be radical.
You're gonna be on fire!
[kids cheering]
How many of you want to be those
who would give out their lives for Jesus?
[kids cheering]
I've got my big old
Goatie Ghost hammer here tonight.
We're gonna break some things in
__ leaves tonight.
We're gonna break the power
of the enemy and government.
They came to your schools
and they took Jesus out of your schools.
But one thing they couldn't do
was take Jesus out of your hearts.
We can't just sit back
and accept corrupt government.
I believe God wants to put
Godly, righteous people in government.
How many of you
want to break this cup?
[people clapping]
Or the power of the enemy
over government.
[people cheering]
Break this cup. You break that thing
in the name of Jesus.
- Righteous government, God.
For righteous government, yes.
- Lord, come on, proclaim
that righteous government.
[glass breaking]
Everytime you break a cup,
there's a release in the spirit.
We break the power of the Devil
in this nation.
- In the name of Jesus, it's gone.
-Shout it out! Shout it out!
I wanna hear you.
[kids cheering]
- Love America.
__ inspire in the world.
In the world!
[shattering glass]
- Jesus!
[together] Jesus!
- Press in, kids. Press in.
Unlike McDonalds,
this is not about how fast
you can go through the drive through.
You want something from God,
you gonna have to cook a little.
You need to stay in the pot
and let him simmer you in the Holy Ghost.
- If God touched you tonight,
I wanna hear about it.
Somebody can tell me what happened.
- Pray it out, Tory.
- Pray it out.
- Take them out, Tory.
- Jesus, help us break the chain
over our nation.
We break the bondage's that --
and we proclaim in the line of Judea.
[people cheering]
Take these prophecies
and do what the apostle Paul said
and make war with them.
[music playing]
This means war! This means war!
This means war!
Are you a part of it or not?
[squeaking metal]
- Tory, over there.
Sorry, I like to throw rocks.
- Okay, Levi, Levi, Levi.
- Whenever I run into a non-Christian
something you know I always...
... You know, there's always something
that doesn't seem right.
There's always something
that makes me feel,
my Spirit feel yucky, you know?
This world, all it feeds you is trash.
It's like giving out candy
but I don't want candy.
I want the meat. The Holy Spirit
is like the meat, good food, you know?
The food that you need
and stuff that is good,
but then, candy would just make you sick.
That's what a lot of people
in this world are, they're sick.
They're looking for something.
[music playing]
- There's a big huge spider back there.
I am not going back there.
- Move over and let me see, where?
- I'll find it.
- Thanks, show me.
- See it?
- You see how big that bug is, Luke?
- No. It's disgusting.
[laughs]
I do think I'm different from other kids
because we know Jesus.
And we're hungering after Jesus,
you know?
But you know what,
I wouldn't be different from other kids
if everybody did their calling.
That's the thing with America.
America, you know, is supposed to be
"God's Nation," right?
But then, things just kind of
started twisting around, you know?
Now, a lot of people in America
are just not following God.
[people talking]
Okay. We're gonna welcome
Mister President now.
Talk to him.
Say, "Welcome, welcome President Bush."
[together] Welcome President Bush.
We're glad you're here.
[together] We're glad you're here.
I want you to bless him.
Speak a blessing to him.
Would you do that?
Reach out and speak a blessing to him.
[people talking]
Do some -- over him.
[foreign language]
He has surrounded himself
with Spirit filled people.
So, pray in the Spirit over him.
Here he is!
He's come to visit us.
Yes, Lord. Thank you, Jesus.
Tell him, Mister President.
[together] Mister President.
One nation under God.
One nation under God!
[audience clapping and cheering]
- Things flew fast, didn't they?
- Yeah.
- They did. They just flew by
and this is the big night.
- Yeah.
- Yeah! Are you ready?
[together] Yeah.
- We've got some good surprises
for you tonight, all right?
Hey, I want everybody sitting down,
hands full and smiling faces,
looking right this way.
[clapping]
- How are you guys?
- I'm very excited tonight.
I usually talk to big people
but tonight I get to talk, maybe,
to the most important generation
in American history.
Whoa! And I'm not just joking.
Who was the young man,
the young man with the long hair?
Right there. Come here, son.
Just stand right with me.
What's your name?
- My name is Levi.
- Levi? Well, that's a great name Levi.
You like Levi's name?
[together] Yeah!
Here's the deal.
Before you were born, God knew you.
Extraordinary. He said this.
He said he formed you
in your mother's womb.
You're not just a piece of protoplasm.
Whatever that is.
[kids laughing]
Not just a piece of tissue
in your mother's womb.
You are created intricately by God.
[children laughing]
Is that incredible!
God wrote a book about your life
and he wrote "Levi. Levi would be
a God seeker from an early age
and he would become a voice
that touched America.
- Yeah!
- And he would not sell out
in his teenage years.
He would go for God all those days
and he'd be a man of prayer
and in his 20s, he'd begin to shake
things real strong for God in the nation.
God's dream. The novel of Levi's life.
Signed, God.
What do you think of that?
- That's pretty cool!
- Pretty cool, huh?
[people laughing]
- Your pretty cool.
[audience clapping]
Now listen to me, guys.
Since 1973, up to 50 million babies
never had a chance to fulfill the dreams
God had for their lives.
That's sad, isn't it?
Do you know a third of your friends,
could be here tonight
but they never made it.
A person is a person, no matter how small.
God has a dream for them
like he has a dream for you.
Do you see that?
It's kind of awesome, isn't it?
Look at that. 7 weeks old.
Tonight, I believe something is gonna
start tonight that can change America.
Seriously.
Kids, I believe that you are
the beginnings
of a movement that can raise up
a moral outcry,
that can overthrow abortion in America
and could turn this.
Would you like to be a part
of that kind of company?
[together] Yeah!
[audience clapping]
I'm sorry.
[together] Jesus, I plead your blood
over my sins and the sins of my nation.
God end abortion
and send revival to America.
Louder.
[together] Jesus, I plead your blood
over my sins and the sins of my nation.
God end abortion
and send revival to America.
- Life! Life ! We command lifeline,
in the name of Jesus. Life!
- Satan in Jesus name, you let go of them.
You have no power taking people's lives.
Only God has that power.
- No more Lord. No more! No more!
No more!
[audience clapping]
- Adults! We cry out to God.
32 years to love!
God we're asking
for the course of America!
We're asking "Shift the course!"
Raise that righteous judges
who will rule
in behalf of your voice, God.
Righteous judges!
[together] Righteous judges!
- In the name of God.
Righteous judges!
- Hear the room, oh God. Hear a room
of children praying to you, God.
Hear from--
Too long Lord!
[together] Righteous judges!
Righteous judges!
-Abortion God!
[together] Righteous judges!
Righteous judges!
- You made a covenant
with God tonight
that you're gonna pray
to end abortion in America.
Don't take that lightly.
Don't be a promise breaker.
Don't be a promise breaker,
be a history maker.
[audience clapping and cheering]
Do you think you know America?
I mean, do you think
you know you're own country?
Well, I gotta tell you, you don't.
There is a religious political army
of foot soldiers out there
that are being directed
by a political right.
This is not the "tin foil hat"
conspiracy stuff, it's happening!
These people,
they don't look like politicos.
They don't look like politicians.
They don't look like they have like,
their on a bandwagon for anybody.
I mean they just look like your neighbor
but when you put them all together,
what ends up happening is they start
taking control in small slices
and so, this is the last stage.
Let me tell you something.
They've taken over the White House,
Congress, the Judiciary for a generation.
Together these people form a powerful,
I mean powerful, voting block.
Look, George Bush and Karl Rove
owe these people big, big time.
We've been asleep at the wheel
as this conservative,
political fundamentalist element
has gained too much control
and power in this country.
I--totally beyond me,
how anybody can look at this picture
and say, "Oh, you know,
this don't affect me,"
is just absurd.
[rustling leaves]
♪ [music] ♪
- I'm pleased to announce my nomination
of Judge Samuel A. Alito Jr.
as Associate Justice of The Supreme Court
of the United States.
-Definitely, if the President tries
to replace O' Connor,
a moderate with an extremist,
it will be the biggest fight
of the Supreme Court
in American history.
[radio channel switching]
-This nomination of Judge Alito
is so important
and why the church needs to be involved.
It's everything, that as Christians,
we care about because he is so outspoken
on the life issue and other issues
that are such great concern to us.
- This is a crucial, crucial time.
Judge Alito,
what he worked on for 30 years,
is coming to culmination,
to conservation, right now.
And let's confirm this man,
Judge Alito for the U. S Supreme Court
and let's make one more step
towards bringing America back to
one nation under God.
God bless you.
[people cheering]
♪ [music] ♪
Colorado Springs has
the greatest concentration
of Evangelical organizations
in America.
Christian tourists
from around the country
are drawn to the city's megachurches.
♪ Your face ♪
♪ is all I see ♪
♪ and your gaze ♪
♪ will always be ♪
♪ my treasure ♪
♪ and my reward, ♪
♪ the one thing-- ♪
♪ Yeah, the one thing I'm living for. ♪
♪ Oh, how amazing ♪
♪ love beyond explaining. ♪
♪ You are beautiful ♪
♪ [instrumental music] ♪
[audience applauding]
- We've decided the Bible
is the word of God.
We don't have to have a general assembly
about what we believe.
It's written on the Bible, all right?
So we don't have to debate
about what we should think
about homosexual activity
it's written in the Bible!
[people talking]
I think I know
what you did last night.
[people laughing]
If you send me a thousand dollars,
I won't tell your wife.
[people laughing]
He talks to President Bush
and his advisers every Monday.
If you use any of these, I'll sue you.
[people laughing]
And I have a 10-year rule about dating.
For those of you that married somebody
30 years older than you,
I hope he dies
so you can get his money.
But...
[people laughing]
The point I wanna get across is
you make sure in your home,
you have a few core beliefs
and we as Americans,
those of you that are
citizens of the United States,
you need to make sure
our nation has a core belief
and as we settle
those philosophies correctly,
then our freedom is guaranteed, amen.
Let's pray together.
Father, in the mighty of
the Lord Jesus,
we pray for President Bush
as he's preparing to elect
a new Supreme Court nominee.
Give us a pillar of strength
that lasts forever.
Lord, let us not waiver.
Let us not be talked out of it.
Let us not be negotiated out of it.
It's massive warfare everyday,
let the battle begin!
Are you getting all this in there?
[people laughing]
Yes. Okay. So you need to repent!
- Man, it's bright.
Yeah, once they turn on
all those lights, it's bright up here.
Hi. How are you doing?
- Hi. What's your name?
- My name is Levi.
- Hello Levi. Ted Haggard,
I'm Senior Pastor here.
- The Senior-- yeah, I guessed.
- Okay. You figure that out?
- Yeah.
- What's your name?
- That was a good sermon.
- Oh, it was a good sermon?
- Yes, it was.
- Oh, you do some preaching?
- Yeah, I preach.
- What's your favorite subject?
- My favorite subject, I like faith.
- Faith?
- That's my favorite.
- Well, that's fabulous.
- Yeah, I like faith a lot.
- So, do people like hearing you preach?
- It seems everybody pays attention more.
You know, "This is preaching."
- Is it your content
or is it because you're a kid?
- I don't know.
- Yeah.
Well, you'll know--
- I guess it's both.
- You'll know when you're 30.
I say, use your cute kid thing
until your 30
and by then,
you'll have good content.
We believe that you have
to emphasize people younger than you
in order for your church
to grow in a healthy way.
Kids are everything.
They love the evangelical message.
God loves them.
The Bible is the word of God.
They are gifts from God.
So while all the public schools
are telling them they're animals,
they're the product of natural selection,
we tell them,
"God loves you. God's created you.
You have a purpose in life."
I mean, the kids are just loving it
and so, it's an awful lot of people
and we're growing.
Churches like this, there's a new church
like this every 2 days in America.
It's gotten enough growth
to essentially sway every election.
If the evangelicals vote,
they determine the election.
It's a fabulous life!
♪ [music] ♪
[sirens wailing]
♪ What can wash away our sins ♪
♪ Nothing but the blood of Jesus ♪
♪ What can make us whole again? ♪
♪ Oh, precious is the flow ♪
♪ that makes us white as snow ♪
♪ No other found I know ♪
♪ Nothing but the blood of Jesus ♪
- Let's sing it for this nation.
♪ What can wash away our sins ♪
♪ Nothing but the blood of Jesus ♪
- Amen. Okay.
The Bible says, "Out of the mouth
of babies, God has ordained praise
to silence the enemy
and the foe and the avenging."
God must have used the smallest
to confound the wise.
The things that are nothing to nullify
the things that are.
You see, the big towers here
in the big buildings
and the big men, God's says the prayers
of little children
can shake kings, come on!
[laughing]
- Hallelujah!
♪ [music] ♪
[dry leaves rustling]
- We're being trained to go out
and train others.
Train others to be God's army
and to do God's will.
What he wants you to do.
- I feel like we're kind
of being trained to be warriors.
Only in a much funnier way.
We don't, like, I don't feel
the sense of, like,
afraid is it to die in battle
or anything, like you would
when you're actually going off
to a war in the physical.
There's a peace with it all too.
There's an excitement
yet peace at the same time.
It's really cool.
- You know, a lot of people die for God
and stuff and they're not even afraid.
They don't need to be afraid of it
or anything.
- It's like, I've heard Dad told me,
like when their dads are like missionaries
and stuff and he's about to go somewhere
really dangerous and stuff,
they jump around and yell,
"Martyr! Martyr!"
It's really cool.
- Go stand right up here in the __,
You could be a young man, Gideon,
Gideon can be mighty warrior for God.
There you go, son.
You stand right there.
Here you go, Joseph.
Someday, you might be the leader
of the government.
You'll never know, Joseph.
Dream dreams.
What's your name?
- Allison.
- Allison. You look great
with that tape on your mouth.
Here we go. All right, here you go,
young man. You're so eager, I love you.
- Some extreme liberals,
they have to look at this
and start shaking in their boots.
The intensity that you see in these kids,
there is no doubt,
they've got to be watching this
and go,
"Oh, my goodness.
I didn't know this is possible.
What are these kids gonna be like
when they grow up?"
It's like animal rights people
eat your heart out, you know?
You wanna see intense.
You wanna see kids passionate
about Christ. This is it!
You know, and I have to believe
with all my heart
that this is just the tip of the iceberg.
I believe those kids
made an impact in Heaven.
God hears the cries of children.
Makes me wanna cry.
[laughs]
[cars passing by]
[phone ringing]
We're talking to Becky,
in Bismark, North Dakota.
She's a Children's Pastor
and she runs a summer camp
for Evangelical children
there in North Dakota.
Becky, how are you?
- I'm doing very good.
- Why kids? Why are they supposed to be
some new Army of God.
Why are we using kids to do that?
- Anyone who does any work with kids
know it's because the reason
you go for kids is because
whatever they learn by the time
they're 7, 8, 9 years old
is pretty well there
for the rest of their lives.
This is the statistics
that you can research for yourself.
- No, I know these statistic
but you use the term, "Learn."
The word "learn" is different
than "indoctrinate." God gave us a brain.
God gave us the freedom to choose
and learning is part of that choice.
I think that everytime
the fundamentalist movement, Becky,
interferes with that, we're doing harm.
We're doing harm
to the progression of mankind.
- I don't think any child
gets anything by choice.
As I understood,
your question to me was,
do you feel its right
for the fundamentalist
to indoctrinate their children
with their own beliefs.
I guess fundamentally-- yes I do!
Because every other religion
is indoctrinating their kids.
Hello! I would like to see
more churches indoctrinating.
- You can tell a child anything.
Just like I said,
you can tell a child,
you can make a child into a soldier
that carries an A.K. 47.
- You could call it brainwashing
but I am radical
and passionate in teaching children
about their responsibility as Christians,
as God fearing people,as Americans,
if you want to--
- Well Becky, let me ask you this.
How do we ignore that all of a sudden,
we're creating children soldiers
for the Republican party?
How does that figure into anything
that Christ had to say about
how we should live our life on the Earth?
- I'm not sure,
I am not aware of any churches
that are out there
with a political cause.
I'm not going after my kids politically
but that, you know,
because at the same time, I wanna say,
and I don't have problems saying
to my children,
"We are Pro Life."
- I got to tell you God is watching us.
God, and God has a very special place
for those people who mess
with our children.
It's not a pretty place.
- You know what,
I'm not gonna go there, Mike.
- You know what's always made
this country special,
what's always set this country apart,
is because there is something that we call
"A separation between Church and State."
That's always something
that separates us
and has separated us for 200 years.
It has worked!
I respect your right as a fundamentalist,
to teach your children whatever
you want to teach them.
But don't let that bleed
over into the public sector.
Don't let that bleed over
into the schools.
- I beg to differ with you.
Christianity is important.
We believe its the most religion
in the world
because it changes
the lives of people.
- But Becky, its a witches brew.
Its gonna take over democracy.
- You know, I think democracy
is the greatest political system
on Earth but that's just it.
It's just what's on Earth
and it's ultimately designed to
destroy itself because we have
to give everyone equal freedom
and ultimately,
that's gonna destroy us.
So the perfect world
is not gonna be perfect
until Jesus is truly Lord.
- Okay. Becky,
thanks for joining us, okay.
- You bet!
- Oh man! The more I hear about this,
it just gets crazier and crazier.
[cars passing by]
[radio on]
- On this vote, the "Aye's" are 58,
the "Nay's" are 42.
The President's nomination has
Samuel L. Alito Jr. of New Jersey
to be an Associate Justice
of the Supreme Court
in the United States, is confirmed.
♪ [music] ♪
- I love America.
I love the American lifestyle.
I love being a part of the 21st century.
I wake up everyday
excited about what I'm gonna do.
But at the same time,
I look at this sick old world
and I go, "God, let's get out of here!"
♪ [music] ♪
Knowing what I know,
how do I not give my whole life
to helping other people?
Children, teenagers, or adults.
Come to a saving knowledge
of Jesus Christ.
How could I enjoy Heaven
the knowledge
that I never told people that meant
so much to me about Jesus.
That is not a burden.
It is the greatest joy of my life.
- The most religious nation
in the world is India.
The most irreligious nation
in the world is Sweden.
We are a nation of Indians
ruled by Swedes.
As Christians, you are the leaders.
You speak for God.
We care about our country.
[people cheering]
And what I wanna say is
we want to get our message out.
We can boil it down
but she said,
"You just boil your message down
to single sentences."
Let me give you some single sentences.
Number 1, its a new day.
Number 2, liberalism is dead.
Number 3, the majority
of Americans are conservative.
Number 4, you can count on us
showing up and speaking out.
And number 5, let the church rise!
[people cheering]
- Thank you Doctor Sutton.
♪ [music] ♪
- Hi!
If you were to die right now,
where do you think you would go?
- Heaven.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Are you sure? Okay.
I think they were Muslim.
I'd like to give this to you.
- No, thank you.
- No, thank you!
- Oh, well. For all we know,
they could be Christians already.
You know what I mean?
Do you think people actually think
we're trying to like
sell something?
- I bet you some of them do.
- We're kids! What are we selling?
- Flyers in our hand.
- God is gonna take good care of you.
You have to stand up on your feet
and praise and magnify the Lord
because he's the one who's set you free.
Praise him.
♪ [ music] ♪